AS ALWAYS,
FOR ALL WHO ARE IN LOVE
AND WHO ARE MEANT TO LOVE
[clock ticks]
[beads rattle]
[mellow music plays]
[music fades]
Just so you know, I don't like you.
I love you.
[gentle music plays]
Should we get married?
Mm-hmm.
[mellow jazz music plays]
[music fades]
[man] Love is an illusion.
[apple crunches]
An illusion
that the one you love is special.
An illusion that you'll
be together forever.
[door closes]
[boy] Where's Dad?
[woman on TV] After years of struggling,
Lee Dong-cheol rose to stardom
with the hit drama Betraying Daffodil.
The country fell head over heels in love
with his now famous catchphrase,
"I'm sorry."
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
[woman on TV] Many rumors
plagued Lee Dong's career.
The most infamous being
that he was married with a secret son.
However, here's a surprise
to dispel that ancient gossip.
Lee recently announced
his surprise marriage
to the daughter of a very wealthy family.
His fiancée is known to be
quite the knockout!
[electricity crackles]
[melancholic music plays]
[man] Mom,
I'm begging you,
please don't let go.
But also, don't think
you need to hold on because of me.
Because if you did,
I'd feel like
as big of a piece of shit as Dad.
[birds chirp]
[music fades]
[woman on PA] The train is now arriving.
[car horns honk, sirens wail]
And this color will look good
with pretty much anything.
It's soft enough for the daytime,
but good enough for night.
STAFF ENTRANCE
[man 1] I don't understand.
Stop giving me excuses!
[man 2] Sir, I'm sorry.
I understand the delay is frustrating.
[man 1] It's your job! What's the problem?
-[man 2] Sorry, go ahead.
-[man 1] This is bullshit!
I'm literally just buying a purse
for my wife.
-I'll be out in two minutes. I can run in…
-[man 2] You can't leave your vehicle.
THE WORLD IS A GIANT TURD
[sighs]
Who are you?
The new part-time guy.
[exhales]
Accepted.
What?
[Bowie fan] I've accepted you
as my new friend.
David Bowie is a god among mortals.
Anyone who knows him can be my pal.
[blows]
[lilting classical music plays]
Everyone say hey to my new amigo.
[woman] Hello.
Say hello. These fine ladies
work at luxury brands.
Chanel. Louis Vuitton. Gucci.
What're you lovely ladies
doing after work?
Should we go clubbing
to break in the newbie?
-[woman] You buying?
-[Bowie fan] They call me Money Bags.
[woman] Ooh, sounds good. Let's go.
No, thank you.
-Why? Why?!
-[music fades]
[people mutter]
-Gotta get home to my cat.
-[Bowie fan sighs]
So what is it? You got RAS?
What's RAS?
It's horrible.
You stop laughing or crying.
Your blood stops pumping and, poof, dead.
Also, you lose all expression.
I don't think so.
Come on, smile.
-Now cry.
-Forget it.
-Yo, lend me your board.
-Excuse me? Why should I?
You know, we're friends.
[funky music plays]
[headphones beep]
[heavy metal music plays]
[music stops]
[lights clang]
[uneasy music plays]
[music fades]
[plays jaunty tune]
[tune ends]
Who is she?
That girl… in the basement.
Saw the dinosaur, did ya?
Can't unsee that shit, huh?
-Dinosaur?
-[Bowie fan] That's what they call her.
She's got a vibe that scares the shit
out of people, kind of like a dinosaur.
[lights clang]
Is she part-time?
[Bowie fan] Nope. She's a full-timer.
Rumor is she got top scores
when they hired her.
[strums ukulele]
You did see how she looks, right?
She was bounced around for a little while,
and no one seemed
like they wanted to keep her,
so she ended up down there.
I'm surprised she's still here,
to be honest.
Anyway, she's pretty weird.
[intriguing music plays]
[man] Don't you just wanna slap her?
[laughs]
[scoffs]
[music fades]
[sneezes]
UTOPIA DEPARTMENT STORE
[intriguing music resumes]
[music fades]
[door closes]
[footsteps approach]
[sneezes]
Whoo-hoo! God.
This blows, huh?
Beers on me?
KENTUCKY PUB
BEAR BEER
[easy listening music plays]
[Bowie fan] My man! Cheers to you, amigo!
Amigo.
You like her, don't ya?
-No.
-Then what is it about her?
I…
just feel for her.
You what?
[sighs] God.
-Ow, man.
-That hurt, bro, didn't it?
Listen to me. You're like these prongs.
Sharp with misguided kindness,
cheap empathy, and one-time humanism.
You can't be poking around
'cause you feel for her.
Especially not you, dude,
with all your rugged good looks.
She'll get hurt.
-I'm nice to her, that's it.
-[Bowie fan] Nice?
There's no such thing
as just being nice and that's it.
I'm telling you, that'll make it worse.
She's already been beaten down by life.
You don't wanna add to it, bro.
Y-You know what really
hurts people like her?
Pity, you moron!
It's pity.
If it's not love, bro,
then keep away from her.
I mean, what is love, huh?
-You wanna know?
-[scoffs]
Sure.
I'll tell you if we go to karaoke.
ONLY LOVE
[cat meows]
[serene music plays]
[music fades]
[man on PA] Friendly team reminder.
Please check to ensure all the souvenirs
were sent to the art hall.
Copy that. Parking team here.
We're helping them out now.
-Go, dinosaur! [roars]
-[men laugh]
[man 1] Glad to be of service!
-[man 2] Wow, look at her.
-[man 1] Oh, she forgot one.
[elevator whirring]
[woman] I don't need help.
I know you don't.
[elevator dings]
["Pavane for a Dead Princess"
by Ravel plays]
[woman hums softly in tune]
You're pretty nice.
[man] My name is Gyeong-rok.
Lee Gyeong-rok.
[woman] My name is Mi-jeong,
Kim Mi-jeong.
[music continues]
[inaudible dialogue]
[music fades]
[Gyeong-rok] How do you know that piece?
Be careful. You stepped in dog crap.
[women laugh]
[panting] You little shit!
[mumbles incoherently]
One, two, three. [mumbles]
[dance music plays]
Whoo!
[laughs]
-Yo-han! Is it true?
-[Yo-han] What?
Apparently, your dad's the owner
of the department store?
Whatever you heard is true!
[gasps] Hear that? He's the owner's son!
Stop listening to gossip.
No, that's what everyone's talking about.
-That's why he can do whatever he wants!
-What's up?
Why would the owner's son work in the lot?
Ah, well, that's all just part
of my management training.
[music distorts]
[music fades]
[Mi-jeong] It's the pavane.
["Pavane for a Dead Princess"
by Ravel plays]
The what?
Uh, the pavane
refers to the music written for a dance,
kinda like the waltz.
It's a classical music phrase.
[Gyeong-rok] Hmm.
"Pavane for a Dead Princess" is
a Maurice Ravel piano piece, and…
Pardon me?
It's one of my favorites.
Oh.
It's nice.
[dance music resumes]
-[woman] Do you have a girlfriend?
-What?
Do you have someone?
I can't hear you.
You're with someone.
Is she pretty?
She must be.
[music stops]
[Gyeong-rok] Do you like classical music?
[Mi-jeong] I like listening to the radio.
FM 93.1.
I like that there aren't any commercials.
[radio static]
[radio host] This next piece is commonly
referred to as "The Skater's Waltz."
Here is "Les Patineurs Waltz"
by Émile Waldteufel. Enjoy.
["The Skaters' Waltz"
by Émile Waldteufel plays]
[Yo-han] Hey! Uh… uh…
Why is the rice yellow?
'Cause it's brown rice.
Oh, brown rice. Got it.
So what's that?
Radish.
It's watery kimchi made with radish.
Ah, radish.
Could I try one, please?
Thanks a lot.
[cutlery clatters]
[containers clatter]
-[music stops]
-Whoa! You see that?
You think they're a couple?
[woman] That'd be crazy.
Do you know? If they're a couple?
-They're cousins.
-[woman] Really?
They don't look alike at all.
Yeah, they're cousins, but pretty distant.
They just met here by chance.
-Small world, huh?
-[woman scoffs] Not a chance.
Hey, even white dogs
have pups that come out yellow.
That's true. I know my grandma's pups
are like that.
Wait, I'll ask them how distant they are.
Hang on a minute.
In pain, man?
Huh?
What about your heart? Does it hurt?
Came in alone today?
[Gyeong-rok] Yo-han's on his way.
Gotcha.
[melancholic music plays softly]
[bell rings]
Good evening!
[gentle music plays]
[Yo-han] Go on.
Don't just stand there. Have a seat.
We're regulars here. Don't worry.
The beer here's great
and it's nice and cold.
-[Mi-jeong] I'm gonna run to the bathroom.
-Sure.
[music fades]
Take your time. Yeah.
-Ah!
-[Gyeong-rok] What the hell?
Oh boy! She's stubborn, that one.
It was hard to convince her to come.
-What are you doing to me?
-[Yo-han] Just do what I tell you.
-First, tell her you're worried.
-Worried?
When she asks why,
you say, "You worry me." Okay?
[groans]
Just something to think about.
There's a girl in there
looking at her reflection
in the mirror, dude.
[soft jazzy music plays]
[blows]
So I'm kinda worried.
What are you worried about?
[whispers] Say that "You're my worry." Go.
I'm not sure
if I should keep living like this.
How exactly are you living?
Just working part-time, you know?
For the love of God. I try to help the guy
and he just shits the bed.
Well, why are you working part-time?
'Cause I wanna go to Iceland.
Go to Iceland
if that's what you really want.
After finishing up in the military,
I was watching YouTube,
and I… came across this video
about auroras in Iceland.
[inhales] And it was just so beautiful.
But in order to get there, I need money,
so I just started working.
And money's okay, so that's good.
But I wonder,
you know, if I'm wasting time.
-[sighs]
-[Gyeong-rok] Every day feels the same.
I used to have another dream,
but that didn't work out.
What was the dream you had?
To be a dancer.
A dancer?
Yeah. Modern dance.
But I stopped.
[sighs] I gave it up.
I guess I thought things would just
work out somehow. I… I don't know. I…
And now I'm not sure
if they ever will, you know?
I don't need to be rich
or be really successful. I just…
I just want to be okay.
[sighs]
Uh, why don't you think of it
as getting off the horse for a bit?
-What?
-[Mi-jeong] You know? A running horse.
The Native Americans?
While traveling on horseback
over long distances,
sometimes they would stop
and get off
and look back at the path they'd traveled.
[gentle music plays]
[Mi-jeong] They didn't do that to rest
or even to let their horses rest.
They did it to wait for their souls
to catch up to them,
in case they were walking slowly.
And as soon as they felt
their souls catch up to them,
they'd start riding their trail again.
So, if you have regrets,
do what you want to do.
Don't waste time with things you don't.
And, you know, instead of doing things
at the pace the world wants you to,
I think it's better
to move at a pace that works for you.
[chuckles softly]
-[fryer rattles]
-Oh.
I've been listening to FM 93.1,
by the way.
Oh, do you like it?
It's great with no commercials.
I know!
Uh, don't you like the master classics
they play at 2:00 p.m.?
The DJ has a nice soothing voice,
and they replay it later at night.
You have a nice voice too.
[quietly] Oh!
[music fades]
What else do you like?
Oh, just anything, you know?
Sure.
Dude, if you just say "sure,"
the conversation just stops.
Here, ask me what I like. Come on.
What do you like?
Ah! Well, if you mean food, I like
paella, rockfish, and tom yum kung soup.
Music? Rock!
Pink Floyd, David Bowie, Deulgukhwa.
Now, movies? Well, I'm a romantic,
Roman Holiday, Breakfast at Tiffany's.
How about you?
-Gone with the Wind, I guess.
-And you?
-Singin' in the Rain is pretty cool.
-[Yo-han] See?
You gotta pass the ball
back and forth like this.
Yeah, romance movies are the bomb.
So what is love, then?
"ONLY LOVE"
"ONLY LOVE" BY BADUKSAN
[in Korean] Love is an illusion.
An illusion
that the one you love is special.
that they're lonely without you.
An illusion that you mean
everything to them.
An illusion
that you'll be together forever.
[distant dogs bark]
[radio host in English] This piece brings
to mind throwing a stone into a lake,
sending gentle ripples
through its very heart.
It's unfamiliar, yet exciting.
Cautious, yet ecstatic.
Dreamy, yet hauntingly beautiful.
Here's a live performance
of "Arabesque" by Claude Debussy.
[applause on radio]
[sighs]
["Arabesque No. 1"
by Claude Debussy plays]
[exhales]
[Mi-jeong groans]
[music stops]
[woman] Luxury brands to storage.
Chanel sandals, J10 black 38, please.
Copy that. Basement storage here.
I'm checking right now.
[walkie-talkie beeps]
[man 1] Golf goods to storage.
TaylorMade men's pants,
7981, black, please.
Copy that. This is basement storage.
Checking now.
OVERSEAS/ACCESSORIES 1F
Did you get hurt?
[Mi-jeong] Ah.
Yeah. Um…
I fell down earlier today.
I'm okay though.
[man 2] Check, check, parking here.
Please check out the spots in Zone A.
[Gyeong-rok] Zone A here.
I copy. Checking now.
[chuckles softly]
["Arabesque No. 1"
by Claude Debussy resumes]
[elevator dings]
[automated voice] Doors opening.
[music stops]
[woman gasps] Oh God! Your face is so red.
You must be slaving away down there.
So he's your cousin?
[Mi-jeong] Sorry?
Gyeong-rok down in valet.
Yo-han said you're cousins though.
Is that true?
Uh…
Yeah.
Let's grab a bite
one of these days. See you.
[automated voice] Doors closing.
Mi-jeong!
Don't worry about it.
I am worried about it.
Well, don't. I'm good.
I'll walk with you.
-[Mi-jeong] You really don't have to.
-You didn't bring an umbrella?
[Mi-jeong] Someone took mine a while ago.
Felt like a waste to buy a new one.
I'm used to it now.
You're used to getting soaked?
No. I'm used to people taking my umbrella.
It is what it is.
It doesn't upset you?
Being in the rain is
a lot easier than dealing with people.
I find that,
for me, it's easier
to just give up instead.
You shouldn't do that.
[Mi-jeong] What?
You shouldn't give up.
You should just take things right back.
How would I do that?
You just go for it.
[Gyeong-rok] Stealing stuff was
a big thing when I was in high school.
Kids were constantly
taking stuff from each other.
It got to the point where one kid
even wrote on his textbook,
"Whoever steals this
won't get into the college they want
and will die without having sex."
[chuckles]
Maybe that's why
I didn't get into college.
And why I might die without having sex.
Mi-jeong…
wanna go somewhere?
WELCOME
[intriguing music plays]
[man] I'm sorry.
Thanks, babe.
You're so strong.
Where are we going?
HOT NIGHT MOTEL
WHIRLPOOL TUB AVAILABLE
FLUTTER INN
[Gyeong-rok] Mi-jeong!
This is it! LP!
ROCK, JAZZ, CLASSICAL
[music fades]
[mellow indie music plays]
♪ Why do I live this way? ♪
♪ Why do I laugh like nothing is wrong? ♪
OLD HITS COLLECTION 1
OLD HITS COLLECTION 2
♪ Why do I keep acting like a… ♪
-Hm.
-[Mi-jeong chuckles]
[blues music plays]
Rock has its roots in the blues.
It's basically playing the blues harder.
Harder than that is heavy metal.
If you don't understand
what they're saying, that's death metal.
What matters is,
if it has the will to change the world,
that's what makes it rock.
See?
Do you play any instruments?
Uh, no, I don't.
But you can dance really well.
Huh?
[Mi-jeong] I saw you dancing.
Oh.
I didn't know.
[Mi-jeong] Yeah. It was nice watching you.
And you were pretty good.
Better not give up on it.
[music fades]
[gentle pop music plays]
[in Korean] ♪ Do you know the feeling? ♪
♪ From the moment I first saw you ♪
♪ It was your face ♪
♪ That lingered in my eyes ♪
♪ Do you know the feeling? ♪
♪ Even the slightest touch
Of your fingers ♪
♪ Fills my heart ♪
♪ With your warmth ♪
[music fades]
[in English] So can I call you?
I don't have a phone.
What?
I got rid of it a while back.
My cell phone. I'm sorry.
Ah.
No, that's fine. Yeah.
How'd you hurt your hand?
Why are you always so nice to me?
Is that a bad thing?
I just don't know how to respond to it.
You can just be nice to me too.
It's simple.
[telephone rings]
[sighs]
[groans softly]
[gentle music plays]
-[panting]
-[music fades]
You guys kiss-kiss?
Did you text her "I love you"?
-She doesn't have a phone.
-Ah, shit. [panting]
Hey, where you going?
[grunts]
FOR YO-HAN ONLY
Bro.
[gentle music plays]
[whispers] Seventeen.
-[walkie-talkie beeps]
-[Mi-jeong] Seventeen.
-Ah, ah. Test, test.
-Are you there?
-[walkie-talkie beeps]
-Copy that. I'm here.
[Gyeong-rok] Where are you right now?
[Mi-jeong] Is everything okay?
[Gyeong-rok] Do you wanna meet up
for a minute?
[elevator dings]
[automated voice] Doors closing.
[door opens]
[sighs happily]
[Gyeong-rok sighs]
[elevator dings]
[music fades]
[woman 1] All right, say cheese!
-One, two three.
-[camera clicks]
Oh, that looks delicious!
Thanks a lot.
[percussive music plays]
-Good?
-[woman 1] Hang on, hang on.
Done! All right, everyone,
go ahead, dig in!
I'm so happy we can hang out
with the people we work with, you know?
It's fun, isn't it?
Yeah, a lot of fun.
I'm very grateful
for all you do down there.
[woman 1] Oh God, me too.
It'd be such a pain in the ass
to go all the way down there
and grab these boxes,
so you bringing them up is great.
So you two are apparently cousins
through your great aunt in-law?
No, first cousins once removed,
so not that distant.
So, Gyeong-rok, who is she?
-What?
-[woman 2] The mystery girl you're dating.
[woman 1] Is she super hot? She must be.
How pretty is she?
Yeah, she's pretty.
And she's grounded and smart.
[music fades]
She's intriguing.
[pensive music plays]
[exhales]
And she's very different
from other girls who…
I mean, when I dated girls before,
it kinda felt like I had to
'cause it was expected of me.
But when I'm with her,
I feel like it's more honest.
I'm not much of a talker in general,
but I can't shut up around her.
I don't think
I'm a particularly great person.
When I'm around this girl, though,
she makes me feel like
I'm a better person.
[Mi-jeong coughs]
And so I think
that's why I really like her, and might--
[all gasp]
-[woman 3 squeals]
-Oh! Uh…
Stop acting like I'm a girl.
-Yeah, we've been dating for a bit.
-[woman 2] Oh.
[Yo-han] So what makes me so different
from all the others, you ask?
Well, I'm older and more experienced.
[music stops]
Come on. Who cares about those guys?
[Mi-jeong sighs]
Yeah, that's really easy for you to say
because you're you and it's different.
Anytime you want, you can just quit,
but I… I need this job.
I need the money,
so I've gotta keep working with them all!
I'm sorry.
Can I say something?
You always keep your head down
even though you've done nothing wrong.
That's not good.
Keep your head up.
Look here. Push your shoulders back.
[inhales deeply]
Hmm.
So what should we do now?
What do you feel like doing?
We can just keep walking
if that's what you want?
I think I'd better get going.
Sorry.
Well, let me walk you.
[Mi-jeong] No. It's really okay.
Oh, uh, my bus is here.
Good night.
[bus brakes squeak]
[bus door opens]
[woman on PA] In three minutes,
we will begin
serving our valued customers.
Please complete all necessary tasks.
FOR YO-HAN ONLY
[Gyeong-rok] Something must be wrong.
She just took a day off.
[background piano music plays]
Say, "Ah." Ah.
Come on, eat it.
Agh!
Oh boy.
I dropped it.
Sorry.
Only care about yourself, huh?
Huh?
I'm a joke?
[gulps]
Get lost.
[music fades]
[man on phone] Three, four, and cartwheel.
One, two, three, and four.
One and two.
Great job, everyone. Great.
All right, that's it for today.
I'll see you all in the next video.
[sighs] Where is she?
[classical music plays]
-[woman 1 on phone] Did you see that look?
-[woman 2] I know! Wow!
I mean, just have a look at that posture.
She's a natural.
We're looking at a true talent right here.
[woman 1] Facial expressions
really do make up half the dance. [gasps]
-Would you look at how cute that is?
-[woman 2] Aw, adorable!
[woman 1] Wow. Look at the expression
on Dong-cheol's face!
[gasps] He's totally captivated
by his little princess.
[girl] This is for my dad, who loves me
more than anyone else in the world!
[Dong-cheol] Wait, stop.
When did you film this?
[girl] I'm so happy and proud
to be your daughter, Daddy.
-I love you so much.
-[Dong-cheol] Aw, I love you too.
[case closes]
[sighs]
[cell phone buzzing]
[Mi-jeong] It's me.
Mi-jeong?
I'm really sorry I'm calling you so late.
I had to go back to my hometown
because there was some stuff going on.
I'm sorry I didn't tell you.
Yeah, I was really worried
that maybe something happened to you.
I'm sorry.
Please stop apologizing. I-It's okay.
[Gyeong-rok breathes heavily]
But is everything okay with you?
[breathes shakily]
Yeah, everything's fine.
[Gyeong-rok cries]
[Gyeong-rok breathes shakily]
Gyeong-rok, it's okay.
I'm going to… come over there and see you.
[stirring music plays]
SLOW DOWN
[Gyeong-rok] Why did you run?
[Mi-jeong] I thought you'd be waiting.
[Gyeong-rok] You could have walked.
[panting]
[chuckles softly]
[inaudible dialogue]
[Gyeong-rok] Mi-jeong…
I always thought
I was the only real one in the world.
Everyone else just felt so fake.
But then, somewhere along the way,
I started thinking
maybe everyone else is real
and I was the fake one.
But when I'm with you,
I feel with every fiber of my being
that we are real.
I like you a lot.
[walkie-talkie beeps]
Mm.
[Mi-jeong] Well…
[inhales]
[music stops]
[breathes shakily]
[exhales]
I also
like you.
[gasping, squealing]
[cheering]
I told you to make sure
you changed the frequency! Jeez.
Whatever, dude.
You can't let those people bother ya.
They're all just a bunch
of sad and lonely bastards.
[chatter, laughter]
[jeering]
Wah!
[sighs] Isn't it so touching?
[scoffs] Yeah, right.
Go cry some more.
I'm serious.
It's really annoying is what it is.
[elevator dings]
[woman] Hang on a second, Mi-jeong.
You should really wear some makeup.
I mean, look at you.
You're dating someone now.
[exhales forcefully]
Okay?
Did I do something to you?
[laughs]
Okay, calm down.
[sighs]
Stop it.
Stop thinking you're that special.
How embarrassing!
How am I supposed to go back to work?
I'm sorry.
Oh, please don't say you're sorry.
Those people just like to be cruel.
Not realizing how much
they're hurting others.
And they don't think about…
the real effect it has on them.
You wanna know
why I don't have a cell phone?
Because it was just people
calling me for money.
My dad's sick. Mom's gone.
And I have two younger siblings.
I had no choice.
Oh.
The loan shark even said that no one
would pay for someone like me.
Gyeong-rok,
did you mean what you said?
-You like me?
-Mm-hm!
Why?
[exhales]
You couldn't ask someone who's trapped
underwater why they're drowning.
How would you?
[gentle piano music plays]
So what now, then?
What do you wanna do?
[music fades]
What about sports? Do you play?
I know where we can play badminton.
I'm good, you know.
I'm good too.
[panting]
[hopeful music plays]
[both grunt]
[grunts]
[groans]
[music fades]
[breathes heavily]
[Gyeong-rok exhales wearily]
[both breathe heavily]
[both chuckle]
And they truly loved one another,
and so they ran off into the sunset.
[lilting piano music plays]
Seriously?
[scoffs]
[music fades]
[sniffs] You do know happy endings
are all just a load of horseshit?
[pub owner] What are you talking about?
Cinderella. You know
how that one ends, don't you?
Not the Disney crap. The real ending.
The happily ever after bullshit
is just for children.
'Cause as soon as Cinderella has a kid,
well, the prince starts looking elsewhere.
For a new woman.
God.
He abandoned Cinderella.
But, see, she's still
gotta raise that kid.
And this kid's
unbelievably picky with food.
Won't eat anything
except for the kimchi his mom cooked.
So, as always, Cinderella fills the fridge
with a bunch of napa cabbage,
radish, and green onions
to make kimchi for her son.
Then she dies.
[chokes]
She hangs herself.
But here's the strange part.
Poor kid doesn't even cry.
He's not sad at all.
After the funeral, he comes home
and, of course, his mom isn't there.
But once
he throws out mounds of napa cabbage,
radish, and green onions
that his poor mom
had stocked in the fridge for him,
the night turns pitch black.
Complete and utter darkness.
And only the light
from the fridge remains.
And as this essentially parentless boy
stares at the fridge light,
finally…
[cries]
…some real emotion takes over.
[melancholic music plays]
[cries] I mean, come on.
[inhales] So Cinderella's son--
-Turn the lights back on.
-Oh, yeah. Sorry, sorry.
THERE IS NO HAPPY ENDING.
NEVERTHELESS…
What you writing?
[Yo-han] A novel.
[pub owner] Oh yeah? What's it about?
[music fades]
Well, uh,
love.
[radio host] This next piece
is "Der Lindenbaum"
from Schubert's Winterreise.
["Der Lindenbaum" by Schubert plays]
[inaudible dialogue]
GOOD LUCK
HOPE YOU GET IN
FINAL SCORE SHEET
DANCE ARTS
[music fades]
[dance music plays]
[woman squeals]
-[man 1] Whoo!
-[man 2] Whoo-hoo!
I'm so happy.
Today is my birthday.
Is it? Congratulations!
Will you kiss me?
Sure. Why not?
[music stops]
[gentle music plays]
I KISSED AGAIN
FOR THE FIRST TIME IN FOREVER
[pub owner] Came in alone today?
Well, I'm always alone.
Why aren't you dating?
[Yo-han] Come on, sir.
You think I waste my time with that shit?
-I'm divorced. Bet you didn't know that.
-[pub owner] Oh.
Long time ago.
Married and separated, yeah.
[sighs] She was a nice person.
I should've lived
happily ever after with her,
but for some reason,
I just couldn't do it.
Divorce sucks, but Dad wanted me
to get back out there.
I got so annoyed
when he tried to set me up with someone
that I showed up with this ugly girl,
said she was my fiancée.
I didn't explain anything to her.
Just told her I'd pay for her time.
But she didn't wanna take the money.
She looked at me with pity.
Fuck me. It was embarrassing.
And then this guy shows up one day after,
and he says he really likes her.
[Yo-han chuckles]
First, I thought
he was just messing with her.
[Yo-han chuckles]
Turned out to be the real thing.
But come on!
How am I supposed to know?
I've never loved or been loved.
I'm a piece of shit, man. A failure.
That's what ran through my head.
Wow, that's a sad story.
Now, sir,
you know that was all bullshit, don't you?
[music fades]
Uh, did you forget
to pay your electricity bill?
It's a little dark.
[Mi-jeong and Gyeong-rok]
♪ Happy birthday to you ♪
♪ Happy birthday, Park Yo-han ♪
[exhales deeply]
[inhales deeply]
[light applause]
I need to make some more money
before I get any older.
Do two or three more jobs.
[Gyeong-rok] Hm.
I could write a best-selling novel
or a movie.
But when I'm 40,
I'm gonna do world tours.
-[Gyeong-rok] World tours?
-Yeah.
Rock band.
[Mi-jeong] Well, me,
I just wanna be a grandmother.
You know, a really cool one.
I know it may sound a bit lame,
but you could eat whatever you choose,
read whatever books you want to, and
just live a full and quiet life.
Mi-jeong and I going to Iceland
is all I want.
I've always wanted that.
It'd be a dream come true.
-Hmm.
-[Yo-han] Nice. Iceland sounds good.
Yeah, auroras, the Blue Lagoon.
When are we leaving? Huh?
You're not.
-I can't come with?
-[Gyeong-rok] Mm.
This is a trip for us.
[sighs]
You son of a bitch. Fine. Go!
You got in? Congrats!
-[sighs] Where's the school again?
-[Gyeong-rok] In Ansan.
[Yo-han] Oh shit, that's far.
[Gyeong-rok] It's not too far by subway.
[Yo-han] We won't be able
to hang out as much.
Things are gonna change again.
What do you mean?
I'll come back a lot.
Nothing's gonna change
'cause I'm at school.
[poignant music plays]
You ever watched Cinema Paradiso?
In the movie,
Alfredo says this line to Toto.
"You can do so much more
with your life, Toto."
"Do it."
"And don't come back."
Then Toto says to Alfredo,
"Grazie. God bless you."
"You have given me
so much, sir. Thank you."
It's beautiful, isn't it? So I say…
"Always cherish
our days together, my friend."
"Because our youth is eternal"
[music fades]
-We want you to leave Korea.
-And we're willing to pay you to do it.
No.
Huh?
Thank you for the offer, but I say no.
You've become a nuisance according to Dad.
[sighs]
Why are you even here now?
Oh, come on. Say what you wanna say.
Hmm? People are watching.
Is this revenge for your mother?
[breathes shakily]
[people chatter, laugh]
[applause]
Welcome!
[all] We love you!
[cheering]
-Oh, he's so handsome!
-[cheering]
Hey there, guys! My name's--
[cell phone rings]
PARK YO-HAN
My name's…
[automated voice] The person
you are trying to reach is unavailable.
Please leave a message after the beep.
Hey. It's Yo-Han.
I don't know if you remember me. We went
to school together. I sat behind you.
You there?
[melancholic music plays]
Long time.
No, it's Yo-han.
Remember now?
Oh, you don't, huh?
You there?
[sighs]
[electricity crackles]
[bell rings]
Hello.
-Still here, huh?
-Yeah.
Take a break and have a drink with me?
I'm prepping for tomorrow.
Ah, come on.
You can prep everything in the morning.
Let's drink.
[pub owner] Nah, it's late.
You should go home.
[sighs]
I'll come back.
[bell rings]
I love you.
[death metal music plays loudly]
[man] Hey! Open the damn door!
It's the middle of the night!
Turn the music down!
Do you have any idea what time it is?
Open up!
[music fades]
[man] I heard he's dead.
Somebody told me it was suicide.
I'd believe that.
-He slit his wrists.
-He's not dead.
So he did it all to get attention or what?
-What? Holy shit.
-Whoa, that's so wild.
If somebody'd told me he was the son,
I'd have made a move.
He is the son, but…
His mom's a mistress! Oh!
Yo-han's mom was a model
at the store here. Pretty nuts, huh?
-So dumb. Why do it?
-Oh!
I'd have blackmailed the owner
for a shitload of cash.
Those wristbands Yo-Han always had on?
Yeah, well, they say they were there
to hide his scars
because it's the third time he's tried.
He always suffered from depression.
But this time, he got up high,
lost it, and jumped off the roof.
-No, he slit his wrists.
-Wanna bet?
[chatter stops]
[Mi-jeong breathes shakily]
[monitor beeps]
[exhales shakily]
[Mi-jeong cries]
[man 1 sighs]
[man 2] Ugh, Jesus.
[Mi-jeong sobs]
Stop crying.
[man 3] Seriously,
what the hell is wrong with that woman?
[man 4] Ugh, Jesus.
I said stop crying!
[Gyeong-rok sighs]
[melancholic piano music plays]
[cell phone buzzes]
GYEONG-ROK:
I’M SORRY…
This painting is Las Meninas.
It shows people's
differing points of view.
SPRING NEW SEMESTER SALE
GYEONG-ROK
[cell phone buzzes]
MISS YOU
WANNA MEET TODAY?
WHAT TIME?
[sighs]
[music fades]
Mi-jeong, what's up?
[student 1] I screwed up my assignment.
[indistinct chatter]
-[student 2] Let's go!
-You should come out.
It'll be fun. I'd really love to see you.
I'll introduce you
to all my friends here. Hmm?
You gonna come?
I'll wait for you.
[Gyeong-rok] No way!
I'm serious. We can't do that.
It's too slow and boring.
We gotta do something fast
and exciting at festivals.
If the music is fast from the start,
people can't follow.
Fine. We can start off slowly
and ramp up to it.
You know, gracefully. Maybe a pavane too.
-[man] Pavane?
-[woman] What's that?
Pavane is like, uh, uh,
music for dance, like a waltz.
♪ Ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba-ba ♪
♪ Da-da-da-da-da-da-da ♪
So we start it off gracefully
with a pavane.
Then, at the right time, we go, bam!
Bam!
-Bam! Bam!
-Oh.
-Hey, boom!
-[man] Da!
Boom! Arms wide out, guys. Hey!
-[woman] Arms out wide!
-Ho! And ho!
-Keep going, and up!
-[woman] Ha! Ha!
Ho! And boom!
-[all] Hoo!
-And hoo!
[all] Hoo! Hoo!
-Ho, ho, ho, ho, hey!
-[applause]
[Gyeong-rok gags]
[Gyeong-rok vomits]
[Gyeong-rok groans]
[Gyeong-rok] This is it.
I live in
unit 101.
Rose Mansion, unit 101?
Well, that sounds elegant, doesn't it?
You think?
It's getting kinda late, right?
I was thinking
we'd have a drink at your place.
I only have tea though.
Is that… okay?
[chuckles softly]
[Mi-jeong chuckles softly]
I'll just go.
Mm.
Have a good night.
[Gyeong-rok] Yeah, take care.
[Mi-jeong] Thanks for everything.
[man] This is Duane Michals'
This Photograph Is My Proof.
His handwritten note reads as follows.
"This photograph is my proof
that there was this afternoon
when things were still good between us,
and she embraced me,
and we were so happy together."
"It happened. She did love me.
Take a look and see for yourself."
And, as happens in life,
he probably looked at this photograph
many years later and thought,
"I wonder where is she now?"
"Did we truly love each other?"
So, in summary,
they were once very much in love,
but it's gone in time.
[melancholic music plays]
[woman] Mi-jeong? Oh, she moved away.
Do you know where she moved to?
No, I'm sorry.
Well, thank you.
Those flowers are all gone.
They've all withered away and died.
[music fades]
[Mi-jeong] Dear Gyeong-rok,
I hope you're doing well.
I apologize for leaving
without saying goodbye properly.
I tried to tell you,
but I just couldn't.
And I shouldn't have done that.
It wasn't fair to you.
I'm
doing well.
[poignant music plays]
[snipping]
How's Yo-han doing?
When I first heard
that he tried to commit suicide,
I thought about the dark side again.
People who have that dark side
deep inside them
feel it's impossible to break out of it.
Ever since I was a child,
I was shut out by everyone else.
And it felt easier to just hide away
with my heart closed off.
And because of that,
I ended up living like I didn't exist
in a dark cave
no one ever dared to come into.
But then one day, I met you.
And you brought me
right out of that dark, empty cave.
You told me not to run away
and that we could just be together.
It turned out that liking someone
wasn't as terrifying as I thought.
But I think that's what made it
feel precious and made me so happy.
But, as more wonderful times
came and went,
I started to get scared.
I thought, "Why am I like this?"
And I wished you were the type of person
who couldn't do anything without me.
I couldn't handle
being that scared and nervous.
Then I suddenly realized that
I think about you all the time
till I fall asleep.
And I miss you
the second I wake up in the morning.
That's why
I had to leave you.
I wasn't running away.
By leaving like this,
I wanted to forever cherish
our amazing time together.
Lastly,
I really wanted to tell you something.
[music fades]
I love you.
Goodbye.
[insects buzz]
[poignant music plays]
[music fades]
[man] Hey, Gyeong-rok!
[chuckles softly]
[gentle ballad plays]
Ah. On your own?
-[man 1] But you did a great job.
-[man 2] I don't know about that.
-Check out that tank.
-[woman] I told him I wasn't ready.
[man 2] The fish are pretty rare too.
-[music stops]
-[door closes]
I thought you went off to school?
Took time off.
Hmm.
Nothing special?
What are you doing after work?
Heading home to see your cat?
[dance music plays]
-Now we run a business together!
-What is it?
-Brazilian waxing.
-What's that?
-It makes you smooth!
-[giggles]
[DJ] Let's go! Go! Jump!
One, two, three, let's go!
[music stops]
Gyeong-rok.
Hmm?
[chuckles]
Gyeong-rok.
What?
[chuckles] Wanna grab breakfast?
LP?
Wanna check it out?
What's that?
Some oldies.
Mm.
[gentle pop music plays]
[in Korean] ♪ Do you know the feeling? ♪
♪ On this road ♪
♪ We once walked together ♪
♪ Your scent still lingers ♪
♪ Do you know the feeling? ♪
♪ Even the slightest touch
Of your fingers ♪
♪ Fills my heart ♪
♪ With your warmth ♪
♪ But between us ♪
♪ There's nothing left ♪
♪ Only a song plays ♪
♪ Like rain ♪
♪ Like the wind ♪
♪ There's nothing left ♪
♪ Only a song flows slowly ♪
♪ Oh, I miss you ♪
♪ Can you hear my heart? ♪
♪ Into this song ♪
[singer on record] ♪ I just pour my heart
And send it to you ♪
♪ Oh, I miss you ♪
♪ Can you hear my heart? ♪
♪ This song comes to an end ♪
-♪ But my heart goes on ♪
-[door opens, closes]
[music fades]
[sniffs]
[exhales]
[sobs]
[poignant music plays]
[in English] Listen to me, amigo.
Know why breakups are so hard?
It's not from the pain of losing someone.
It's more because…
even for just a small period of time,
you felt alive with that person.
And now that feeling's gone,
and it's so painful
you'd rather be dead.
Oh, stop joking about dying, would ya?
Just be good to this girl, man!
Don't lose interest
because she's not as pretty as others.
Oh, dude! No, Mi-jeong's so beautiful.
You think?
Do you know what love is, Yo-Han?
What?
It's looking into someone's very soul
and seeing how radiant it is.
And seeing someone's soul shine
is beautiful.
So that's why Mi-jeong is perfect to me.
[laughs]
[Yo-han laughs]
[both laugh]
[music fades]
Come on, smile.
Now cry.
UTOPIA DEPARTMENT STORE
STAFF BULLETIN BOARD
Oh. [chuckles] Hey, Se-ra.
I'm sorry. Are you busy?
No, I… I'm not busy.
I mean, why the hell would I be busy, huh?
Want some coffee? Maybe grab some food?
[chuckles] That's okay.
Would you let me take a look
at someone's personnel file?
It's just, she's not here anymore.
[footsteps approach]
Gotta say,
you're an asshole.
[exhales]
KIM MI-JEONG
398-57 GYOHA-DONG, PAJU-SI, GYEONGGI-DO
[rain stops]
[sighs]
[Gyeong-rok] Dear Mi-jeong,
I miss you.
I really wanna see you.
So on December 24th,
from 5:00 p.m. onwards,
I'll be waiting at Jangjawon bus stop.
If you don't wanna meet me,
you don't have to come.
But I hope you do.
I wanna see you.
I miss you.
[radio host] Next up, we have Chopin's
"Nocturne No.21", opus posthumous.
Here it is.
["Nocturne No. 21" by Chopin plays]
4:28 P.M.
THURSDAY, DECEMBER 24
[man] Ah, Christ.
[music fades]
[siren wails]
EMERGENCY SERVICE
[indistinct chatter]
4:47 P.M.
THURSDAY, DECEMBER 24
[Gyeong-rok sighs]
[panting]
[breathes heavily]
[Mi-jeong] Why did you run?
[Gyeong-rok] The bus
broke down in the snow.
[Mi-jeong] You could've walked.
I was starting to think
you might not come.
[Gyeong-rok] But you still waited.
[gentle ballad plays]
[waiter] Here you go. Enjoy.
[clears throat]
Yo-han, is he… doing well?
Mm. Yeah, he is.
[kettle whistles]
[waiter] I'll be in the back.
Just ring the bell if you need me.
[music fades]
[crockery rattles]
[Mi-jeong] We should probably get going.
Why?
The bus'll stop.
[romantic jazz music plays]
[Gyeong-rok] Wait.
[inhales]
How about a dance?
No, I can't.
[music fades]
Get home safe, okay?
Okay. Bye.
[door closes]
[bus engine revs]
[brakes squeal]
Huh?
[bus door opens]
[romantic music plays]
[Gyeong-rok] Mi-jeong!
We're getting back together, right?
We have to!
[gentle music plays]
I love you so much!
I can't break up with you.
We have to be together forever!
Because I love you!
When can I see you again?
Next week?
I'll meet you at Kentucky Pub
on December 31st at 3:00 p.m.
[chuckles softly]
Let's go somewhere nice.
And eat some good food,
and then watch a movie.
[exhales sharply]
Maybe a concert after that?
That sounds great. I'd love to!
[Mi-jeong] Mm.
We'll go to a concert
and then go hear the New Year's Eve bell.
You need to promise me we'll meet then.
'Cause if you can't do that,
if you don't come…
I don't know what I'll do.
[romantic music swells]
[gentle music plays]
[chuckles softly]
[radio host] So here we are
on the last day of the year,
and tonight, the New Year's Eve
bell-ringing ceremony
will be held at Bosingak in Seoul,
delivering a message of hope.
It promises to be pretty packed
as folks gather
to bid farewell to this past year
and usher in the new one.
Traffic control will be
in effect this evening.
[distant dance music plays]
[music stops]
[bell rings]
[classical music plays]
Welcome to
Classical Music Meets Literature.
-We have an author with us today.
-[music fades]
Interestingly, your book shares its title
with one of Maurice Ravel's pieces.
Are you a big fan of classical music?
[Yo-han] I like
rock.
[radio host] David Bowie?
For sure. Yeah, I love all kinds of music.
I'm in a band too.
Yeah, you should, uh, come see us play.
Thanks, I will.
5 YEARS LATER
Please tell us a bit about this book.
PAVANE FOR A DEAD PRINCESS
It's really about the love story between
two close friends I met a few years ago.
-Obviously, the main character's me.
-[radio host] Right.
And, yeah, back then,
I didn't know
if life was worth living.
I'd complain and ask these dumb questions.
Then I started spending time
with these two people
and began to feel hopeful.
So it's how they helped me grow.
Thanks so much for sharing that.
Are these two lovebirds
still doing well now?
Definitely.
Because our youth is eternal.
-[boy groans]
-[jaunty tune plays on piano]
One, two, three, four!
[in Korean] ♪ I’m a mole ♪
♪ A cool, black mole ♪
♪ A sleepyhead during the day ♪
-[in English] Starts dancing like this.
-[laughter]
[pot hisses]
[Mi-jeong] Thirty-one,
thirty-two, thirty-three.
PARK YO-HAN
43-78, WAUSAN-RO 24-GIL, MAPO-GU, SEOUL
PAVANE FOR A DEAD PRINCESS
[page turns]
MEETING HER
LOVE IS AN ILLUSION
[Yo-han] Love is an illusion.
An illusion you'll be together forever.
She waited and waited for him that night,
but he never came.
"He must've abandoned me,"
she thought to herself,
and so she left.
[sighs]
But the truth was
his bus had collided
with an oncoming truck
on the icy road that night.
[horn honking]
["Pavane for a Dead Princess"
by Ravel plays]
[tires screech]
After a long period of rehab,
he was finally able to walk again.
But due to partial memory loss,
it was almost impossible
for him to lead a normal life.
[chuckles softly]
[Yo-han] Love is an illusion.
An illusion you'll be together forever.
What it's really about is understanding
and accepting each other no matter what.
After all, love is
about imagining.
[music fades]
It's something that lives on
as you dream that someday
you'll meet again.
I love you.
[exhales shakily]
[cell phone buzzing]
[Yo-han] Hey, Mi-jeong, did you read it?
What do ya think?
Think I've got a major bestseller
on my hands or what? Huh?
Come on, seriously, what do ya think?
It's all about you and Amigo.
It's just… [sighs]
…too happy at the end, you know?
[Yo-han] I wanted it to end like that.
Remember the Native Americans?
[gentle music plays]
That story you told?
You said that
when they'd ride their horses,
they'd sometimes stop
and get off for a while
to wait for the slow souls to catch up.
You know, Mi-jeong,
I think Amigo just got off his horse
for a minute.
Maybe he's waiting for us
to catch up somewhere.
YO-HAN, GYEONG-ROK & MI-JEONG - FOREVER!
THE LATE LEE GYEONG-ROK
[Mi-jeong] How are you doing these days?
That night, the night of the snowstorm,
I shouldn't have let you go like that.
I regretted it,
and I've felt guilty ever since.
Though I've never forgotten about you…
I let myself remember our moments together
for the first time in a while.
[bell tinkles]
[inaudible dialogue]
I think I'm able to continue living,
continue pushing forward,
thanks to the light that you gave me.
I know someday we'll meet again.
And I hope
you can hang on until then.
PAVANE
[music fades]
[rock music plays]
Hey, look!
Amigo!
[hoofbeats]
[horse neighs]
[poignant rock music plays]
[music fades]
[gentle pop music plays]